Finding Aid for the Antony Balcena Papers LSC.0625
UCLA Library Special Collections
Antony Balcena papers
1974-2001
UCLA Library Special Collections
Balcena, Anthony
LSC.0625
8.0 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
Antony Galindo Balcena, a Mexican-American, was born in Lompoc, California on April 30, 1954 and died in Los Angeles, California on November 23, 1995. Antony Balcena, (also known as Tony Balcena) was an accomplished dancer, choreographer, and Gay and AIDS activist. He was known for his unique choreographic style and, through his life, he created and performed intimate and controversial performances such as "Dudes" and "Shell of Flesh." This collection documents the life and work of Balcena as a choreographer, dancer, and Gay and AIDS activists.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio and audiovisual materials. Audio and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Griffin, Michael, 2002.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9960755453606533
Biography
Antony Galindo Balcena, a Mexican-American, was born in Lompoc, California on April 30, 1954. Antony Balcena, (also known as Tony Balcena) was an accomplished dancer, choreagrapher and Gay and AIDS activist.
Balcena started taking dance classes at the Riverside Ballet Arts Theater, Riverside, California, in the early 1970s. In 1974 he decided to audition at the Juilliard School of Dancing and was accepted, and later earned his B.F.A. in 1977. He continued his studies and got a M.A. in Dance from UCLA in 1984 and a M.F.A. in Dance from Arizona State University in 1992.
Balcena began his dancing and choreographic career in New York City where he worked on and off Broadway. Balcena dancing style was influenced by the work of Daniel Lewis, who taught him the Limon technique. He worked with Daniel Lewis Dance Repertory Company from 1975 to 1981. Balcena's career covered dancing and bodybuilding. He worked as a professional bodybuilding coach for many years. From 1983 to 1990, he staged and choreographed several bodybuilding competitions (Mr. Olympia, Ms. Olympia, Mr. America and Mr. Universe).
In the 1980s, Balcena returned to Los Angeles where he worked with Sarah Elgart and Co. (1982) as a dancer and eventually became Assistant Director. In 1989 and 1990 he participated in the Los Angeles Dance Kaleidoscope presenting several dancing productions (e.g. "Dudes"). During the 1990s he also choreographed several controversial works about AIDS (e.g. "Shell of Flesh," "AIDS! The Musical"). He also worked as assistant choreographer for films such as "Earth Girls Are Easy" and "Rented Lips."
Balcena received several awards and honors during his career. In 1991, he won a choreographic award from the Nuevo L.A. Chicano Danceworks Festival, and an Award of Merit from the Juilliard School Alumni Association's Los Angeles chapter. He also worked for several years (1983-1993) as an instructor at Loyola Marymount University, Cal State University San Bernardino, and Plaza de La Raza, a Mexican cultural arts center. In 1994, he joined the Dance faculty at Arizona State University. He died on November 23, 1995 of complications resulting from AIDS.
Sources: ASU Insight, October 21, 1991. AIDS! The Musical program brochure, ca. 1991. DUDES, Press release, 1989 OLIO, Sunday, March 28, 1982 Vol. 6. No. 4 AIDS Wall in Protest, http://www.geocities.com/WestHollywood/Heights/3957/ The Estate Project for Artist with AIDS, http://www.artistswithaids.org/artforms/dance/catalogue_index.html Mike and Tony, documentary by Wm. Grimes, 2001.
Different names used by or used for Balcena: Anthony Balcena, Antony Balcena, Tony Balcena, and Anthony Galindo Balcena.
Scope and Content
This collection includes videotapes and audiotapes of Antony Balcena's choreographic work from 1974 to 1995. It also consists of publications (novels and newspapers clippings), unpublished materials (theses and typed manuscripts), production materials (programs, flyers, postcard ads), photographs, and slides relating to the life and work of Antony Balcena. A variety of publicity materials (flyers, photographs) to promote his choreographic work supplement this collection.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection was originally arranged in boxes with books, typed manuscripts, photographs and video and audiotapes without any apparent order. The series names were assigned by the processor. The collection was arranged in the following series: 1. Publications (Books, Newspapers clippings) 2. Unpublished Papers (Typed manuscripts, theses) 3. Slides 4. Photographs 5. Videotapes (VHS, BR20 and BR30 tapes) 6. Audiotapes (5" and 7" audiotapes) 7. Production Papers (programs, flyers, postcards ads, publicity photographs)
Mexican American dancers -- United States -- Archives.; Choreographers -- United States -- Archives.; Balcena, Antony--Archives.
- Audiotapes
  - Choreographic Music, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    7 in. audiotape titled: "In Time of Conflict" Note reads: 1971 by Larry Delinger Chored: Antony Balcena Juillard 1974.
  - Chiten, Paul, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Spirit of LA" by Paul Chitens
  - Delinger, Larry, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Delinger" Note reads: Sitting Delinger Quietus © Larry Delinger 1975-1976. All rights reserved. 7 1/2 ips mono 2 tracks side 1 only.
  - Partch, Harry, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    7 in. audiotape. Side I has Harry Partch talking about the unique instruments he had created. Side II, titled "Delusion of the Fury," has music composed by Harry Partch and conducted by Danlee Mitchell. The tape included a card with the information about the recording.
  - Partch, Harry, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    7 in. audiotape. Continuation of the previous audiotape [Box 12 F. 4.] Titled "Delusion of The Fury (A Ritual of Dreams & Delusion)". Side III and Side IV has music from this composion by Harry Patch and conducted by Danlee Mitchell. The tape included a card with the information about the recording.
  - Posing Music, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Posing Music for Jessica and Frekas. 000- Part 1 0560 Part 2." Note reads: 15 ips 4 tracks.
  - Various Choreographic Music, ca. 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Chiten and Arboretum/zoo" Note reads: Composed and Performed by Paul Chiten. Choreographed by Antony Balcena. "Radha"--7 1/2 track; "Going" 7 1/2 track; Loyola Marymount University. "Arboretum Zoo;" "Accidental Suicide;" "Oscillae;" "Chiten" 7 1/2 4 Track Tale out. 7.5 ips 1/4 track stereo heads.
  - La Malinche music, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    5 in. audiotape titled: "La Malinche." Note reads: 7 1/2 ips 1/4 track stereo Rehearsal only. Good music.
  - Agent Orange Nightmare Music, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Agent Orange Nightmare" Note reads: Choreographer: Antony Balcena. Music: Mark Schafer and "Two Poems" etude Op 42 #3 by Alexander Scriaban/Performed by Vladimir Horowitz. 15 stereo 1/2 track Tail Out.
  - Choreographic Music and a letter (Box 13, Folder 3)
    7 in. audiotape titled: "Simon" Note reads: 7 1/2 ips 1/2 track mono copy. A letter was included inside the tape. Letter re: suggestion using the music for a choreography by Balcena. It is signed by Dianne.
- Photographs
  Photographs (black and white and color), negatives and positives
  - Dancing Pictures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Color prints (4" x 6") of some theatical production with Balcena dancing together with other people. Positives (test sheets) of a selection of the same pictures. The folder also includes negatives of same pictures.
    Positives of selected pictures taken by Steven Baratz © 414 Riverdale Dr. Glendale 91204. 818-240-5189. Negatives probably taken by Raymond Garcia 931-8037.
  - Various Photographs, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Prints without labels and dates that can identify the pictures with the people portrayed in them. Two photos do have the name of the photographers.
- Production Papers
  Production Papers (programs, photos, negatives and other related materials of a theatrical production)
  - Dudes, AIDS! The Musical, DART company, 1980, 1989, 1991, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Production materials from two different musical production directed and choreographed by Antony Balceda, "Dudes" (1991) and "AIDS! The Musical" (1989). Re: AIDS epidemic. The folder includes brochures, photos, positives (test sheets) and correspondence related to these productions and a dance group called DART Company.
  - Publicity Materials, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Prints, flyers and programs for different productions (e.g. "Men," "Dudes," and "Image of Hope").
  - Programs and Publicity Material, 1982-1994, broken series (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Programs, flyers and postcards from a variety of choreographies and/or musical plays that Balcena participated, e.g. "The Feast of All Souls;" "Oscillate;" "Annual Spring Dance Concert" at Loyola Marymount (1985, 1990-1991, 1993); "Crossed Lines;" "Brigadoon;" "Mi Hija, Mi Hermano;" "Dudes;" "AIDS! The Musical!." There are several programs from the Sara Elgart & Company where Balcena was a dancer and Assistant Choreographer.
- Publications
  Publications include: books, magazines, newspapers (whole or clippings), publicity materials (business cards, advertising postcards, brochures), and Press Releases.
  - Publicity Materials, 1977, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Advertising postcards for the musical play, "AIDS! The Musical" in 1991. Brochures from the Juilliard School on their dance works in 1977. Balcena business cards for his Hollywood studio.
  - Griffin, Michael, 1990, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Letter to the Los Angeles Times editor responding to an article written by Elaine Minamide (also included) re: homophobia. Editorial pages of the Los Angeles Times. Excerpts for Griffin novel titled "Nationwide Butterpump."
  - Press Releases and Newspapers Reviews, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Three Press Releases: "Dudes" (1989), "Shell of Flesh/Silence to Say Goodby" (1993), and "Shell of Flesh," as part of the Day Without Art (1990). Newspapers Reviews of different musical plays: "Dance Kaleidoscope: Shell of Flesh" (1989), "Agent Orange Nightmare," and "Shell of Flesh" (1990). Newspapers articles re: Promotion of Day Without Art as part of World AIDS Awareness week (1991, 1993), Balcena going to Arizona State University (ASU) as a graduate student (1991). There are two (2) black and white photographs used as part of the publicity for "Dudes." One was taken in 1994 at ASU by James Corwlin and another one, n.d., was taken by Raymond Garcia. Also, Balcena's resume updated to 1990.
    James Cowlin photo included his address and the negative info: Image Enterprises 751 E. Belmont Ave. Phoenix, AZ 85020, 602-944-3266, © 1994.
  - Newspapers Reviews and Programs Materials, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Reviews for the musical plays "Dudes" and "AIDS! The Musical!" Photos and flyers for "Dudes." Program for the musical play "West Side Story: A Charity Parody."
    Publicity photo by Raymond Garcia.
  - Newspapers reviews, Articles, Press Releases, 1977-1993, broken series (Box 2, Folder 2)
    The folders have several newspapers, whole and clippings, with articles and reviews of Balcena choreographies, dancing roles, boydbuilding jobs, and AIDS activism activities in which he was involved. Articles re: AIDS plays and charities; jobs at Loyola Marymount in Los Angeles and Arizona State University (ASU) at Tempe; acquiring degree at ASU; Daniel Lewis Dance Company. Reviews re: "Shell of Flesh," "Dudes," "AIDS! The Musical," "West Hollywood Story: A Charity Parody," "Gee, I'm really not supposed to be here." Press release re: "Shell of Flesh," "Shard Psalm Triptych." There is also publicity materials such as advertising postcards, and photographs.
  - Newspaper reviews and interview, 1982, 1990, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    3 newspaper reviews (e.g. "Mi Hija, Mi Hermano;" "Shell of Flesh;" "Shard Psalm Tryptych") and a newspaper interview with Balcena in 1982.
  - AIDS Activism, 1987, 1990, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Newspapers clipping of news re: ACT-UP and other gays and AIDS activist groups re: protesting Government policies against HIV/AIDS infected people; news of AIDS conferences. ACT-UP and Gay and Lesbian group handbooks.
- Slides
  - Various Dance Performance Slides, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    40 slides of various dance performances taken between 1977-1978.
  - Various Dance Performance Slides, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    5 slides of various dance performances taken in September and October of 1978.
- Unpublished Papers
  Unpublished Materials (thesis, school papers)
  - M.A. Thesis, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    A copy of the Anthony (Galindo) Balcena Master of Arts' thesis, from the University of California, Los Angeles, titled "Literature into Dance: The Aesthetics of Yukio Mishima."
  - MFA's Thesis, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    A copy of the Antony Balcena Master of Fine Arts's thesis, from Arizona State University, titled "Shard Phalm Triptych."
  - Santería: A Kinesthetic Profile, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    A school paper titled "Santería: A Kinesthetic Profile" done for the course Music of the Caribbean MHL 598, Dr. Ted Solis, instructor.
  - Dead Lungs Breathe, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    A short story called "Dead Lung Breathe," inside a longer typed manuscript. First page is numbered 176 and last page is numbered 181.
  - Kicks in the Eye, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Typed manuscript of the novel "Kicks in the Eye" by M. Dylan Griffin. Included a Author's Note that dedicated the novel to Anthony Balcena. One of the main characters in the novel, Gabe, is based on Balcena.
- Videotapes
  VHS, BR20, BR30 tapes
  - Choreographies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    2 VHS tapes with choreographies by Balcena. One is titled, "Antony Balcena, Movement Director/Choreographer-Sample Reel" (Sample of works such as Fashion and Rock Videos, Bodybuilding and Playboy) and other tape is titled, "HIGHWAYS: Razorblades, Lightbulbs and A Royal Heart" (Sat. 3/6/93).
  - Choreographies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    2 VHS tapes with choreographies, one by Balcena and another by Sarah Elgart. One is titled, "Tony - AIDS Day 12-1-93- A.S.U." and the other is titled "Pushing Back-- Sara Elgart KCET Excerpt--Judy Garland."
  - Documentary, Book and Choreography, 1990, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. A documentary short (2001) by Wm. Grimes titled "Mike and Tony." Re: Balcena's AIDS diagnosis, last days in hospice, his relationship with Mike (Michael) Griffin. And a video of the dance-play "Shard Psalm Tryptych" created and choreographed by Antony Balcena. The folder also included a book by Michael Griffin (1990) titled "Nationwide Butterpump." Excerpts from this book--which is marked throughout with yellow post-it notes--were used in the dance-play "Shard Psalm Tryptych."
    The yellow post-it notes marked the pages where text was taken for the play.
  - Choreographies, 1988, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Westlake School for Girls Westside Story" 3/18/88 Length: 1:59:53 Bill Walter. The other is titled: "Balliano Presents: Dances and Songs from Il Decamerone Di Boccaccio." 6/25/91 /#6722/ 38 minutes.
  - Dances and Choreographies, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "1991 Annual Spring Concert" and the second video is titled: "TV tape" [modern ballet taped from TV.]
  - Choreographies, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Love Letters Excerpt by Sarah Elgart." Rehersal choreography. The other is titled: "Rooms" a dance-play.
  - Choreographies, 1983-1986, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Choreographies" by Antony Balcena. The video includes these choreographies: "Oscillate" 83-84 UCLA; "Mishima" '84 UCLA; "Arboretum Zoo" '85 LMU; "Radha" '86 LMU; "America is Waiting" (Elgart) LMU '86. The second video is titled: Antony Balcena "Agent Orange Nightmare" (8:03): "Iscukkate":(12:26) 4/11/91 Loyola Marymount U.
    UCLA= University of California, Los Angeles. LMU= Loyola Marymount University.
  - Choreographies, 1986, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Intro Choreo Modern III Videolog" 10-9-89. And the other tape is titled: "Choreographer Showcase '86 w/Dudes."
  - Choreographies, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Tony 3-87 Work" and the second tape is titled: "The Waldstein Sonata Indianapolis Theatre."
  - Choreographies, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Collection of Older Works - Oscillate- Excerpts of Rooms. ASU 11/93." Alternate titled: "Mi Hija Mi Hermano Christ" and written over in black marker COW. Second tape is titled: "NC School of the Arts The Curtain Rises Dub of BC4551."
  - Choreographies and Sample Work, ca. 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Various Choreographies SE (Sarah Elgart) & Co." Intro/Crowds "Kalisdescope" '84. "Marrying the Hangman," "Bugle Boy/UNO;" "Daffy Fashion Video/Lifes a Beach." The second tape is titled: "Antony Balcena, Movement Director/Choreographer-Sample Reel." The tape includes the following samples: "Fashion Videos," "Rock Video," "Bodybuilding," "Playboy."
  - Choreography and Conference, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Forum For New Art" 11-12-91 ASU, the other is the other is titled: "Winter Crane- Monk Solo."
  - Choreographies, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Tony Balcena #114 Bags" and the other is titled: "Mi Hermano, Mi Hija" By Antony Balcena April 14, 1993. 13:10
  - Choreographies, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: Antony Balcena "Men's Trio" with comments on the cover that reads: Balcena- Choreography Chiten, Rehearsal of New Work, Added Works. Second tape is titled: "Oscillate 2nd 1/2" using for DART '93-94 Tour. On inside label a note that reads: "Oscillate": Antony Balcena 1979 Music Philp Glass.
  - Adult Movie and Choreography, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled "Rites of Winter," an adult movie copyrighted to Vivid Videos Inc. Second video is titled: Antony Balcena Choreographer "Bastard Reel' 5/89.
  - Adult Movie and Choreographies, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One is an Adult movie titled "Rednecks Working." Second video is titled: Antony Balcena "Agent Orange Nightmare" (Solo) 8:03 and "Oscillate" (Group) 12:26.
  - Choreographies, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Scratch." The choreography with Balcena started in video the time counter of 350. Second tape is titled: "Margaret."
  - Family Gathering and Choreography, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "For Tony July 24, 1993." A family gathering with Balcena present with friends and family. Second tape is titled: "Antony Balcena Excerpts selected to demostrate various styles of choreography." "Guilt" (Excerpt from "Shard Psalm Triptych") (Spoken Word) 1992 Arizona State University Dance Laboratory. "Oscillate" (Lyrical) 1991 Loyola Marymound University and "Agent Orange Nightmare" (Social/Political) 1991 Loyola Marymound University.
  - Choreographies, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Various Choreographies: Chiten, Radja (Rehearsal) New Oscillate, Added Loyola Works." On inside label note reads: Loyola Marymount 1984 "Chiten," Rehearsal New "Oscillate" @ Loyola 1985. On outside tape sleeve note reads: Antony Balcena "Men's Trio" (10:36) 4/26/88. Second video titled: "Work Tape." Re: Balcena choreography working tape.
  - Adult movies, 1984, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. Both are adult movies. One is titled "The Rites of Fall" and the other is titled "WM. Higgins' Class Reunion."
  - Sample Reels, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. Both made by Vista Media in different dates (09/24/87) and (04/27/88). Both tapes are VHS Dub, time length 5:24.
  - AIDS! The Musical! Part 1 and 2, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. Both are titled: "AIDS! The Musical!" One is part 1 of 2 and the second is part 2 of 2. The rest of the labels reads: First Incarnation High Ways August 1991 Program Material Copyright 1991 All Right Reserve. Written in red pen (on both tapes): David Stanley's
  - TV Shows and Movie, 1984, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Kooky Classics with Shari Lewis." A MGM/UA Home video, time length: approx. 54 minutes. Second video is titled: "Reg E Rock" A Security Pacific Video, time length: 12:00 minutes.
  - Choreography and Musical Play, 1989, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "DART Tour '94 Dobson High." Second tape is a musical play titled: Alan Nicholson in "Love Can Make You Crazy!" © 1989 Baskerville Productions.
  - Dancing and Modeling Tapes, 1987-1988, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "La Blanca 1987/1988" Re: modeling. Time length: 60:00. The second tape is titled: "The Girls of The Cabaret Royale." Time length 57:05. Playboy Enterprises,Inc. 10/22/91.
  - Sample Reel and Dance Excerpts, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    A Master Broadcast Videocassette and a VHS tape. The master is titled: "Antony Balcena, Movement Director/Choreographer-Sample Reel." The tape includes the following samples: "Fashion Videos," "Rock Video," "Bodybuilding," and "Playboy." The VHS tape is titled: "Rooms"--Excerpts in Order for LMU Dance Tour 1988-89. "Intro Going" * "Womens Trio" (Day Dream), "Woman's Solo" (Escape) "Sextet" (Desire) "Outro" (Finalí).
  - Choreographies, 1986-1987, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One tape is titled: "Sarah Elgart and Company Excerpts from Cmpany Repertoire": "Marrying the Handman," "Strategies," "Recess" and a broadcast version of "Deeper Reasons"(1986-87). Second tape is titled: "Shell of Flesh/Silence to Say Good-bye." Day w/o Art. Cal Museum of Photography Antony Balcena 12/1/90 c/o ASU Depart of Dance box# 870304.
  - Choreographies, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One tape is titled: "Danceteller Presents "Before Forever" a dance" re: living with AIDS. Running Time: 81 minutes. Second tape is titled: "1. Waldstein 2. Trio."
  - Choreographies, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Two VHS tapes with three different versions of the dance-play "Mi Hija, Mi Hermano." One tape is titled: "2 Diff Versions Mi Hija Mi Hermano." Second tape is titled: "Mi Hija, Mi Hermano" (Stacey) © A. Balcena.
  - Documentary and Choreography (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Two VHS tapes. One is a documentary titled: "Common Threads Stories from the Quilt: The fabric of lives joined together by a shared fate: AIDS" Narrated by Dustin Hoffman. Second tape is a dance-play titled: "AIDS! The Musical! Reheasals!"
  - Choreographies, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Two VHS tapes. One is titled: "Candice Solo & End," "Mi Hija, Mi Hermano." Second tape is titled: "Spring Dance Concert 1987."
  - Rock Video and TV Shows, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Two VHS tapes. One tape is titled: "Stock Exchange" [cabaret show] and "Louise Hay on Oprah Winfry". Second tape is titled: "Hot Sauce" Thomas Dolby 4:15, Antony Balcena choreographer.
  - Music Video Choreography and Fashion Video, 1986, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)